Guide to the Merle Hoffman Papers, circa 1944-2012 and undated, bulk 1961-2000 RL.00557
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- On the Issues Series, 1980-2000 and undated, bulk 1990s, 27 boxes
  - Administration Subseries, 1987-2000 and undated
    - Publishers' workshops and notes, 1992-1993 (Box OTI26)
    - Resumes and samples - artists, 1991-1993 (Box OTI26)
    - Resumes
      - Art directors, 1993-circa 1994 (Box OTI26)
      - Book reviewers, 1994 (Box OTI26)
      - Editorial and marketing, 1987-1993 and undated (Box OTI26)
      - Executive editor, 1993 (Box OTI26)
      - Freelancers (copy editors, line editors, proofreaders, fact checkers), 1997 and undated (Box OTI26)
      - On file, 1992 (Box OTI26)
      - Writers, 1997 and undated (Box OTI26)
    - Royalties
      - Copyright Clearance Center, 1994-1998 (Box OTI26)
    - Royalties (Box OTI27)
      - New York Times syndication, 1995-1997 (Box OTI27)
      - Uncover database, 1995 and 1997 (Box OTI27)
      - University Microfilms, 1992-1998 (Box OTI27)
    - Staff/contributors' biographical notes for web site, 1998 (Box OTI27)
    - Subscription/circulation contractor - Fulco, 1995 (Box OTI27)
    - Subscription procedures, 1995 (Box OTI27)
    - Subscriptions - complimentary, 1997-1998 and undated (Box OTI27)
    - Subscription services contractors, circa 1988-circa 1990 (Box OTI27)
    - Subscription services contractors - correspondence and statistics, 1988-1990 (Box OTI27)
    - Subscription services - financial report, 1995 Oct. (Box OTI27)
    - "To do - waiting for calls to be returned," 1997 and undated (Box OTI27)
    - Web site printout, 1995 (Box OTI27)
    - Web site work (Stephanie Brail), 1994-1995 (Box OTI27)
    - Web site work (Sara Yager), 1998, 3 folders (Box OTI27)
  - Electronic Format Subseries, 1985-1998
    Disks contain article drafts, mailing lists, advertisement text and graphics, a reader survey, and other files pertaining to the publication of On the Issues.
    Electronic documents have been transferred from their original computer disks to the electronic records server. Files originally located on the same disk have been kept together on the server, in subdirectories labeled by disk number. These disk numbers do not reflect Hoffman's own labels or arrangement of the disks; the numbers were assigned to the original computer disks in the order they were received. This original order has been re-arranged alphabetically by supplied title as described below.
    There are also a few On the Issues electronic documents located in mixed-file groups in the Personal Series Electronic Format Subseries.
    - Article "Lluisa Vidal, Daughter of Modernism," 1998. Disk 063: "Lluisa Vidal Text OTI c:\wp51\misc\llvidal.oti", 1 file (Box OTI27)
    - Articles, and Merle Hoffman open letters, 1989. Disk 017: "#20A Duplicate, OTI XII," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 69 files (Box OTI27)
    - Articles and other issue materials
      - 1985-1988. Disk 008: "Disk 15A vol. 8 duplicate copy," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 33 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1988. Disk 012: "Disk 18A, duplicate disk, OTI IX, Spring 1988," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 21 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1988. Disk 013: "Disk 18B, OTI IX, duplicate disk," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 45 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1988-1989. Disk 014: "#19 Duplicate," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 36 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1988-1989. Disk 015: "#19A duplicate," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 39 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1988-1989. Disk 016: "OTI Vol. XI, #20 (Duplicate)," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 42 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1989. Disk 018: "#20B, DUPLICATE," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 30 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1989. Disk 019: "#20C, DUPLICATE," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 30 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1990. Disk 041: "Disk 29A", 45 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1991. Disk 036: "Vol 19", 9 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1991. Disk 037: "Duplicate Vol OTI 21 Disk 33", 45 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1991. Disk 035: "Disk 34, OTI Vol 22", 66 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1992. Disk 040: "Disk #35, OTI Vol 23", 31 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1992. Disk 039: "Volume 24 Disk 36", 63 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1992. Disk 038: "Vol 24 Disk 36A", 21 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1992. Disk 034: "Duplicate #37 Vol 25", 18 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1992. Disk 043: "Duplicate #37A - Vol 25", 48 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1988. Disk 011: "Disk 18 duplicate, OTI vol. IV, Spring 1988," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 9 files (Box OTI27)
    - Articles, correspondence with advertisers, and mailing lists, 1985-1988. Disk 047: "Disk #3 Spec Typing, Vol VII OTI, Duplicate Disk", 60 files (Box OTI27)
    - Article, Sherryl Kleinman, "The Nose Job, 1998
      - Disk 069: "Kleinman, 'The Nose Job', 3 files (Box OTI27)
      - Disk 070: "Kleinman, 'The Nose Job' (in text, RTF, and WP 4.2 formats)", 3 files (Box OTI27)
    - Articles, other issue materials, and two files on Choices newsletter, 1985-1987. Disk 009: "Disk 16 OTI, 7/87, duplicate disk," in box labeled "7/88 15A-20C", 42 files (Box OTI27)
    - Article, "Worldwide Inequality Forces Girls into Sex Trade," 1997. Disk 068: "Wordperfect 6.1 Andrea D'Asaro Piece for Summer 1997 OTI", 1 file (Box OTI27)
    - Correspondence (one file), Choices Chatter (one file), and On the Issues articles, 1985-1989. Disk 045: "MH-2B Duplicate", 21 files (Box OTI27)
    - Donor mailing lists, form letters, and subscriber mailing lists, 1986-1988. Disk 031: "#14 OTI -- subscribers + donors, duplicate disk," in box labeled "7/88 7A-14A", 75 files (Box OTI27)
    - Graphic of Cambridge sign, 1996. Disk 075: "Cambridge photo: domestic violence-free zone Jane Tyska 1996" [removed from folder Artworks and Advertisements, 1994-1996 and undated], 1 file (Box OTI27)
    - Mailing list of Women's Studies programs, 1998. Disk 067: no disk label [removed from folder Women's Studies Mailing], 1 file (Box OTI27)
    - QuarkXPress advertisement, 1998. Disk 064: "'Teen Voices' Ad for 'On the Issues' 12/15/97", 4 files (Box OTI27)
    - QuarkXPress advertisement and graphics
      - 1995-1996. Disk 058: "Deming ad for On The Issues, New Victoria Publishers, P.O. Box 27 Norwich, VT 05055", 5 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1996. Disk 052: "Ad for Eve's Garden, Gwen Croft 212-489-7833", 12 files (Box OTI27)
      - 1996. Disk 053: "Eve's Garden, Jan 96 for On the Issues/Spring, Gwen Croft Graphic Design, Mac and Traditional, 420-422 W. 47th St. #2C New York, NY 10036, 212-489-7833", 9 files (Box OTI27)
    - Reader survey and production to-do list, 1997. Disk 062: No disk label [removed from Jan Goodwin files], 3 files (Box OTI27)
- Personal Files Series, circa 1944-2001 and undated, bulk 1961-1999, 25 boxes
  Documents Hoffman's work as a public speaker, organizer, and political activist for abortion rights and other feminist causes. The series also contains some records of Hoffman's childhood and personal life. There are detailed records for the New York Pro-Choice Coalition, founded by Hoffman as an umbrella organization for New York City pro-choice groups and active during the late 1980s. Other organizations represented in the series include the National Organization for Women (NOW), the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), and the National Association of Abortion Facilities (NAAF).
  Arranged into the following subseries: Correspondence, Writings and Speeches, Subject Files, Politics and Activism, New York Pro-Choice Coalition, Calendars, Phone Messages, Clippings, General Personal Files, and Electronic Format. Materials related most directly to Hoffman's personal life are concentrated at the end of the series in the General Personal Files. Other subseries focus on her political life as feminist activist. A number of subseries contain some materials on Choices Women's Medical Center or On the Issues magazine.
  - Correspondence Subseries, 1946-2000 and undated
    Offers a mixed selection of Hoffman's communications with fellow activists and friends, chiefly from the 1970s through the 1990s, although there are some letters from earlier years. Arranged alphabetically by name.
    - Chesler, Ariel - recommendation, 1995 (Box P1)
    - Chesler, Phyllis, 1994-2000 (Box P1)
    - Colquitt-Craven, Cynthia (Wright), 1979-1982 (Box P1)
    - Dix, Laurence, 1988-1989 (Box P1)
    - General correspondence, 1974-1999, 3 folders (Box P1)
    - Hoffman, Jack, 1946 (Box P1)
    - Kinzel, Walter - postcard and articles, 1964-1965 and undated (Box P1)
    - Letters home from Europe, 1964-1968 and undated, 2 folders (Box P1)
    - Mixed Choices/personal correspondence, 1980-1982, 1991, 1994-1995, 3 folders (Box P1)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), 1983-1992 (Box P1)
    - Public response to media appearances, 1979-1989 (Box P1)
    - Savvy magazine - thank-you note and sample issues, 1980 and undated (Box P1)
    - Stoltenberg, John, 1991-1992 (Box P1)
  - Writings and Speeches Subseries, 1960-2001 and undated
    Provides supporting materials for Hoffman's professional publications on women's health care, her rally speeches, press releases, and many other public expressions of her political activism. The subseries also contains material on her cable access talk show, "On the Issues," as well as student papers written by Morgan during the 1970s. See the Audiovisual Series for additional interviews and debates, as well as for video recordings of Hoffman's cable television show "On the Issues." Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - "Abortion: A Different Light" documentary announcement, 1982 (Box P2)
    - Abortion, AIDS, and women's health issues - writings and public statements, 1981-1986 and undated (Box P2)
    - Abortion debate and interview, Boston television, 1981 (Box P2)
    - Abortion debate - Queens College, 1986 Feb. (Box P2)
    - Abortion debate - Rockland County National Organization for Women, 1981-1982 (Box P2)
    - Abortion debates - facts file, 1981-1982 and undated (Box P2)
    - Abortion speech, Brown University, 1990 (Box P2)
    - "Abortion: the Politics of Violence" conference paper and addendum, 1985 (Box P2)
    - "Abortion: the Politics of Violence," First Annual National Nursing Conference on Violence against Women, 1985 (Box P2)
    - "Abortion: the Politics of Violence" journal article, 1986 (Box P2)
    - "Abortion: the Politics of Violence" panel, American Medical Women's Association conference, 1985 (Box P2)
    - Abortion violence open forum, Cafe Nexus, 1985 Feb. 10 (Box P2)
    - Abortion violence speech - references, 1983-1985 (Box P2)
    - "Aborty, Politika, Istoriya, Filosofiya" (Moscow), 1992 (Box P2)
    - Central Park jogger rape case, public statement and New York Amsterdam News editorial, 1990 (Box P2)
    - "Family Planning and Abortion Counseling" presentation, Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, 1981-1982 (Box P2)
    - Federal Women's Program speaking engagement, 1985 (Box P2)
    - "Feminism, power, politics, abortion," Journal of the American Medical Women's Association, 1985 Nov./Dec. (Box P2)
    - Feminist Majority Expo, 1996 (Box P2)
    - Film and Abortion conference, Hampshire College, 1982 (Box P3)
    - First Unitarian Church sermon on abortion, 1986 (Box P3)
    - Friends of Animals, Ecovisions conference, award acceptance speech, 1994 (Box P3)
    - "The Global Mandate for Choice" (Russia), 1992-1993 (Box P3)
    - Health care editorials for 1991 New York Times, 1990-1991 and undated (Box P3)
    - Holocaust Museum - notes, draft, and background materials, 1993 and undated (Box P3)
    - "How the Women's Movement Is Improving Medicine," Newsday, 1978 Sept. 10 (Box P3)
    - Kennedy, Florynce ("Flo") - funeral, 2001 (Box P3)
    - Letters to the editor, 1981-1986, 2 folders (Box P3)
    - Long Island Pro-Choice Coalition rally, public statement, 1992 July (Box P3)
    - Mental Health Community Breakfast, 1995 (Box P3)
    - Midday Live Show on firing of single, pregnant teacher, 1986 (Box P3)
    - National Abortion Federation (NAF), conference (1996 Mar.), 1996-1997 (Box P3)
    - National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL) rally, 1985 Jan. (Box P3)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), Clinic Defense Conference, 1990 (Box P3)
    - NOW-Nassau Chapter, award acceptance speech, 1995-1996 (Box P3)
    - NOW-New York City, awards ceremony and acceptance speech, 1998 (Box P3)
    - NOW-New York City, awards ceremony - speech as event chair, 1999 (Box P3)
    - New York Pro-Choice Coalition rally, 1986 Jan. 22; 1987 Jan. 22; 1988 Jan. 22; 1988 Apr. 29, 4 folders (Box P4)
    - Noga magazine with Hoffman article (in Hebrew), 1998 (Box P4)
    - Notes for speeches, 1999 and undated (Box P4)
    - Over-the-counter contraceptives, 1979-1982 and undated, 3 folders (Box P4)
    - Over-the-counter contraceptives, Los Angeles Times editorial, 1982 (Box P4)
    - On the Issues cable access show
      - Administration, 1985-1986 (Box P4)
      - Publicity, 1986-1987 and undated (Box P4)
      - Scripts and story ideas, 1985-1986 and undated (Box P4)
    - Patient power and abortion rights - writings and public statements, 1973-1982 and undated (Box P4)
    - "Patient Power" article for Hot Flash, State University of New York at Stonybrook, 1982 (Box P4)
    - "Patient Power" article, 1982 and undated (Box P4)
    - "Praise the Lord and Kill the Doctor," circa 1994 (Box P5)
    - Press release on Bishop Daily prayer vigil, 1990 June 9 (Box P5)
    - Pro-choice editorials, 1981-1982 and undated (Box P5)
    - Pro-choice rally, Albany (1990 Jan. 21), 1989-1990 (Box P5)
    - Public statements and clippings, 1975-1992 (Box P5)
    - "Quiet Heroines" and "Once More into the Breach" typescripts, 1985 and undated (Box P5)
    - Radio interviews and other press, 1995-1996 (Box P5)
    - Radio-TV Interview Report, advertisement for Hoffman as pro-choice spokeswoman, 1995 (Box P5)
    - Satya magazine interview and sample issues, 1995-1996 (Box P5)
    - "Seeing the Light: Reflections on Women and Power"
      - Typescript drafts, circa 1981 (Box P5)
      - Revisions, circa 1981 (Box P5)
      - Submission and rejections, 1981 (Box P5)
    - O.J. Simpson verdict - Los Angeles Times editorial, 1995 (Box P5)
    - O.J. Simpson verdict - publicity for Los Angeles Times editorial, 1995 (Box P5)
    - Student papers, 1961-1970s (Box P5)
    - Student papers and appeals letter, 1970s (Box P5)
    - Student papers and school honors, 1971-1973 and undated (Box P6)
    - Student papers - English, 1960-1964 and undated (Box P6)
    - Rodriguez, Ana - editorial draft, undated (Box P6)
    - "A Room without Flowers," article on AIDS for New York Native, 1985 Oct. 21-27 (Box P6)
    - "Russian Roulette: The Women's Version," letter to the editor, 1982 (Box P6)
    - Sam Townsend Interview Show, 1983 (Box P6)
    - Suffolk Community College, Women's Week, 1990-1991 (Box P6)
    - Tanenbaum, Leora - interview for book, 1997 (Box P6)
    - Todos Santos Business and Professional Women meetings, 1985 (Box P6)
    - TV interview transcript, 1981 Oct. 16 (Box P6)
    - United Nations Conference on Women (Beijing, 1995) - panel talk, 1995 (Box P6)
    - Unnecessary hysterectomies - interview planning, 1981 (Box P6)
    - Violence, Abuse and Women's Citizenship conference, "Global Abortion Rights," 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box P6)
    - WNBC-TV interview transcript, Merle Hoffman and Jeanne Head, 1984 Feb. (Box P6)
    - Wolf, Naomi, Our Bodies, Our Souls - response, 1995 (Box P6)
    - "Women's Health - An Oxymoron?" editorial draft and pro-choice media campaigns, 1991-1993 and undated (Box P6)
    - Women in Crisis conference, Women and Power panel, 1980-1981 (Box P6)
    - "Women in the Health Care System: the 'Medical Mystique,' " Colloquy, 1983 Apr. (Box P6)
    - "Women's Role in the Health Care System" and conference talks, 1978 and undated (Box P6)
  - Subject Files Subseries, 1978-1997 and undated
    Primarily concerns abortion, including informational material produced by various pro-choice organizations. Abortion-related subject files are grouped separately at the beginning of the subseries. See the Politics and Activism Subseries and the Clippings Subseries for additional pro-choice publications and other materials.
    - Abortion, 1978-1997 and undated
      - Abortion Providers History Project, 1994-1997 (Box P7)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), legal updates, 1989 and undated (Box P7)
      - ACLU, Reproductive Rights Update, 1989-1997, 2 folders (Box P7)
      - Anti-abortion literature, circa 1989 (Box P7)
      - Anti-abortion violence - news articles, 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box P7)
      - Baird, Bill, 1978-1979 and 1987 (Box P7)
      - Clippings and pro-choice mailings, 1984-1985 (Box P7)
      - Congressional mailing list and abortion stances, 1995 (Box P7)
      - Fact file
        - 1987-1992 (Box P7)
        - Clippings, 1987-1992, 2 folders (Box P7)
      - Fact file (Box P8)
        - Conscience newsletter, 1989-1992 (Box P8)
        - Lawsuit against Operation Rescue, 1989 (Box P8)
      - Fund for the Feminist Majority, information sheets, 1989 and undated (Box P8)
      - Glamour abortion article with Hoffman quote, 1983 May (Box P8)
      - National Organization for Women (NOW) information kit, 1989 (Box P8)
      - National pro-choice organizations, response to anti-abortion violence, 1994 (Box P8)
      - New York magazine with abortion article and Hoffman photo, 1989 Sept. 18 (Box P8)
      - Operation Rescue, 1984-1989 (Box P8)
      - Parental consent court cases, 1989-1991 (Box P8)
      - Parental notice/parental consent laws, 1983-1990 and undated (Box P8)
      - Planned Parenthood of Southeastern Pennsylvania v. Casey, 1992 (Box P8)
      - Pro-choice clippings and pamphlets, 1997-1998 and undated (Box P8)
      - Reproductive Freedom News, 1992 Sept.-1995 Mar. (Box P8)
      - Silent Scream debate, 1985 (Box P9)
      - Studies and reports, 1979-1995 and undated (Box P9)
    - General Subject Files Subseries, 1982-1997 and undated
      - American College of Women's Health Physicians, 1997 (Box P9)
      - Astraea National Lesbian Action Foundation, 1995 (Box P9)
      - Charlotte Bunch, "Women's Rights as Human Rights" typescript, circa 1990 (Box P9)
      - Conference - "Breaking the Cycle of Dependency," 1982-1984 and undated (Box P9)
      - Falwell, Jerry, 1985-1986 and undated (Box P9)
      - Family and divorce/Phyllis Chesler materials, 1985-1986 and undated (Box P9)
      - Ferraro, Geraldine, 1985-1986 and undated (Box P9)
      - O'Connor, John, Archbishop-Designate - interview transcript, 1984 Mar. (Box P9)
      - O'Connor, John, Cardinal - clippings, 1989-1991 (Box P9)
      - Orbach, Susie, "Body Image," bulimia article, 1985 Oct. (Box P9)
      - Over-the-counter oral contraceptive debate, 1993 (Box P9)
      - Souter, David, Supreme Court nomination, 1990 (Box P9)
  - Politics and Activism Subseries, 1968-1999 and undated
    Documents Hoffman's participation in pro-choice and other political organizations. In addition, it includes files on her individual political activities, especially her support of and donations to political candidates. Hoffman's husband Martin Gold established a political action committee, the National Liberty Committee, in the early 1980s. In the 1990s, Hoffman established the Diana Foundation to serve as a conduit for her donations to various individuals and causes.
    - Animal rights
      - Humane Society contribution, 1981 (Box P9)
      - National Alliance for Animals annual meetings, information packet, 1991 (Box P9)
      - Women and animal rights conference, planning, 1991 (Box P9)
    - Diana Foundation
      - Bill Baird, 1999 (Box P9)
      - Carol Bower, Cape Town Rape Crisis, 1997-1998 (Box P9)
      - Guerilla War Against Abortion Survey, 1997-1998, 2 folders (Box P9)
    - Elections
      - Catherine M. Abate (New York State Senate), 1995 (Box P9)
    - Elections (Box P10)
      - Carol Bellamy (mayoral campaign), 1982-1985 and undated (Box P10)
      - Joe Biden (presidential campaign), 1987 (Box P10)
      - Campaign contributions, 1982-1988 and undated (Box P10)
      - Deborah Glick (Manhattan Borough President), 1996-1997 (Box P10)
      - Elizabeth Holtzman (Brooklyn District Attorney), 1984-1986 and 1997 (Box P10)
      - Betty Lall (Congressional campaign), 1984 and undated (Box P10)
      - Ruth Messinger (City Council), 1987-1992 (Box P10)
    - Fund-raiser invitations, 1985-1986 and undated (Box P10)
    - Mayor's Domestic Violence Colloquium, 1996, 3 folders (Box P10)
    - National Association of Abortion Facilities (NAAF), 1976-1977 and undated, 2 folders (Box P10)
    - NAAF - Newsletter, Summer 1976 (Box P10)
    - National Abortion Federation/National Abortion Council/National Association of Abortion Facilities, 1977 and undated (Box P10)
    - National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL) and "Sex Survival Van, or Save Our Children" speech notes, 1985 (Box P10)
    - [NARAL fundraiser?], guest book, circa 1984 (Box P10)
    - NARAL fundraiser - planning, 1984 (Box P11)
    - NARAL - Tribute to Providers, 1985-1986 and undated, 2 folders (Box P11)
    - National Liberty Committee
      - Federal Election Commission reports, 1981-1987 (Box P11)
      - Martin Gold, 1981 and undated (Box P11)
      - Mailings, 1981 and undated (Box P11)
      - Tax forms, 1981 (Box P11)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW)
      - Annual convention, 1991, 1992, 2 folders (Box P11)
      - New York City, award to Merle Hoffman, 1988 (Box P11)
      - Pro-choice march, 1989 and undated (Box P11)
    - National Women's Political Caucus, New York State Biennial Convention, 1990 (Box P11)
    - Pro-choice conference materials, 1996 (Box P11)
    - Pro-Choice Summit - planning, 1997 and undated (Box P11)
    - Refuse and Resist! (Box P12)
      - Newsletters, flyers, concert materials, 1998-1992 (Box P12)
      - Conference, 1996 (Box P12)
      - National Day of Appreciation for Abortion Providers, 1996 (Box P12)
      - Resist in Concert! December 4th, 1988, The Palladium, NYC (Box P12)
    - Reproductive Rights Coalition, "Principles of Unity" and letter, circa 1989 and 1990 (Box P12)
    - Sexual Liberalism and the Attack on Women conference, 1987 (Box P12)
    - United Nations Conference on Women (Beijing, 1995)
      - 1985-1995, 2 folders (Box P12)
      - "Beijing reportback, 10-25-95-MH," 1995 (Box P12)
      - Bringing Beijing Home program, 1995 (Box P12)
      - Merle Hoffman, identification badge, 1995 (Box P12)
      - Travel and registration, 1995 (Box P12)
    - Women and Power conference materials, 1968 and 1981 (Box P12)
    - Women's Health Equity Act, New York City Council hearings and Hoffman testimony, 1979 and 1990-1991, 3 folders (Box P12)
    - Women's Health Equity Act, U.S. Congress, 1990, 2 folders (Box P12)
  - New York Pro-Choice Coalition Subseries, 1979-1999 and undated
    The New York Pro-Choice Coalition was organized by Hoffman in 1985, and was active until approximately 1990. The Coalition organized annual pro-choice rallies, shared information and coordinated security measures among member organizations, and dealt with the New York City government on abortion and clinic security issues. Minutes and meeting materials are placed first in the subseries, organized by meeting date. Meetings were generally held at least once, usually twice a month. Meeting files contain agendas, minutes, attendance lists, announcements from member organizations, and correspondence or other materials related to the meeting agenda. All other files are organized chronologically at the end of the subseries. See Oversize Materials for additional financial records.
    - Minutes and Meeting Material, 1979-1999 and undated
      - 1985 (Box P12)
      - 1986-1989 Apr. 11, 26 folders (Box P13)
      - 1989 June 6 - 1990 Mar. 20, 12 folders (Box P14)